Main navigation
---------------

Show search field

Back to top

Privacy policy
==============

**Please read this policy carefully to understand how we collect, use and store your personal data.**

WaterAid understands that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate you trust that we will do so with the utmost care.

We take your privacy seriously and are committed to protecting your personal information.

WaterAid America has created this Privacy Policy to explain why we collect particular information and how we will protect your personal privacy within our Web site. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the Web site located at the URL www.wateraid.org/us.

WaterAid America, a US 501(c)(3) non-profit organization, is the United States member of WaterAid, an international federation of international development organizations with members in the UK, Australia, Sweden and Japan (collectively “the WaterAid federation”). References to WaterAid and/or WaterAid America collectively apply to the WaterAid federation and WaterAid America as may be applicable.

In order to fully understand your rights we encourage you to read this Privacy Policy as well as our Terms of Use. WaterAid America reserves the right at any time and without notice to change this Privacy Policy simply by posting such changes on our Site. Any such change will be effective immediately upon posting.

Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, this Privacy Policy notifies you of what personally identifiable information of yours is collected through the Site; How such information is used; With whom your information may be shared; What choices you have regarding collection, use and distribution of your information; What kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control; and, How you can correct any inaccuracies in your information.

What information we collect and how we use that information:

We collect two types of information, Standard Web server traffic pattern information, and information collected through our registration forms and when you make a donation via the Web site. Standard web server traffic pattern information is comprised of general traffic, site usage, and length of stay information which is collected and stored in log files. This type of information is shared externally, if at all, only on an aggregated basis.

Our registration forms require users to give us contact information that may include name, email address, format preference (HTML vs. Text), mailing address, phone numbers, interests, and similar information. We use this information to contact you should there be a question about your donation and we also use this information to personalize communications to you to keep you informed about our programs and progress. We will use your email address to contact you about our programs unless you opt out in accordance with this Policy. We do not request or store sensitive information from our visitors, such as credit card or social security numbers. WaterAid America may keep a record of which links you click within emails in order to gauge the effectiveness of email marketing.

Like many other non-profits, WaterAid America shares basic user information with other non-profits to better serve our users and the mission. If you do not wish to share this information, you may opt out by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.wateraid.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

If you do not wish to receive these communications, or if you would like to change the frequency or types of communications you receive from us, simply click the unsubscribe link in any email or contact us and we will be pleased to respect your wishes.

Internet protocol address:

We collect an IP address from all visitors to our Site. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Site, analyze trends, track users' movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the site, and deliver customized, personalized content. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

Use of "cookies":

Our Site may use cookies to enhance your experience while using our Site. Cookies are pieces of information that some Web sites transfer to the computer that is browsing that Web site and are used for record-keeping purposes at many Web sites. Use of cookies makes Web-surfing easier by performing certain functions such as saving your passwords, your personal preferences regarding your use of the particular Web site and to make sure you don't see the same ad repeatedly. Many consider the use of cookies to be an industry standard.

Your browser is probably set to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to have your browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of our Site will not function properly when you view them.

Security:

All information provided to WaterAid America is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us.

Access:

Upon request, we will provide you with the contact information we maintain about you so that you may request corrections or provide a change of address. This information will be sent via postal mail, which we believe is the most secure method of communication. Please contact us in writing at: 233 Broadway, Suite 2705, New York, NY 10279.

To protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before providing information or making corrections.

Third party websites:

Our Site may contain links to other Web sites which are not under the control of WaterAid America. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another Web site for which WaterAid America has no responsibility. Inclusion of these links is for your convenience only and to enhance your experience on the WaterAid America Web site. It does not imply an endorsement by WaterAid America. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on all such sites as their policies may be different than ours.

Your options:

We respect your privacy and allow you to restrict internal and external sharing of your personal information. We recognize that you may wish to limit the ways in which we contact you and we offer the following options should you contact us and wish to opt out of receiving communications from us:

Do not contact me by telephone (phone call)

Do not contact me by SMS text message

Do not contact me by postal mail.

Do not contact me by email.

Do not contact me with fundraising requests supporting WaterAid America.

Do not contact me

Do not share my information.

If you do not wish to receive any email communications from us in the future, please contact us or click the ‘Unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of any email you receive from us. If you contact us with an opt-out request, all reasonable efforts will be taken to ensure that you will not receive any of the selected communications from us in the future. If you do not wish to opt out at this time, you may do so at a later date should you so desire.

Policy updates:

We reserve the right to update this policy at any time. Any new version will be posted on this Web site. Your continued use of the Web site constitutes your agreement to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If a material change is made to the policy, we will email all registered users at the email address provided at time of registration.

Copyright:

This Web site and the materials on it are owned by WaterAid and/or WaterAid America. Reproduction of this material in other publications or on other websites requires the express written permission of WaterAid and/or WaterAid America. All rights reserved.

Your California privacy rights:

If you are a resident of California, you are entitled to request the following information which we will provide to you free of charge:

A list of the types of personal information which we disclose to third-parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year;

The names and addresses of all third parties that receive personal information in these categories from us in the preceding calendar year and examples of the products or services marketed by these businesses.

name and address;

electronic mail address;

age or date of birth;

names of children;

electronic mail address of children;

number of children;

the age or gender of children;

height;

weight;

race;

religion;

occupation;

telephone number;

education;

political party affiliation;

medical condition;

drugs, therapies, or medical products or equipment used;

kind of product purchased, leased or rented by customer;

real property purchased, leased or rented;

the kind of service provided;

social security number;

bank account number;

credit card or debit card number;

payment history;

information pertaining to assets, liabilities or credit worthiness.

Please direct your request for these types of information to the address under “Contacting the Web Site,” below.

Contacting the website:

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, you can contact:

WaterAid America

233 Broadway, Suite 2705, New York, NY 10279

[\[email protected\]](https://www.wateraid.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

212-683-0430

Footer
------

### About WaterAid

### Get in touch

### Useful info

* [Stories from the field](https://www.wateraid.org/us/stories-from-our-work-around-the-world "There are over 29 million water stories we could tell. These are just a few of them. (1386)")

WaterAid is a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization (EIN/ tax ID number 30-018-1674).  
WaterAid America, 233 Broadway #2705, New York, NY, 10279  
WaterAid - the water, sanitation and handwashing charity | © Copyright WaterAid - All rights reserved.  

* [\[email protected\]](https://www.wateraid.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
